Guide to the Matthias B. Tallmadge Papers 1715-1868 MS 612
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Legal, 1772-1829, undated
  - Subseries II.C: Handwritten Notes, 1800-1813, undated
    - Mounted Notes on Cases in New York District Court, 1809 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Mounted Notes on Cases in New York District Court, 1810-1813 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Mounted Notes on Cases in New York District Court, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Mounted Notes on U.S. v. Aquila Giles, Nicholas Fish, and Matthew Clarkson, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Subseries II.D: Tallmadge Family Documents, 1829, undated
    Subseries D is very small and consists of personal legal instruments for the Tallmadge family property.
    - Tallmadge Family Legal Documents, 1829, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Series III: Notes and Ephemera, 1771-1825, undated
  This small series, mostly not dated, provides a look into the Tallmadge family life. There are documents relating to finance and property as well as hymns and poetry. Of note in this series is the folder Hymns, Poetry, and Narratives. Within that folder is testimony from Susan Wright, one of the Clinton family's slaves who became a Baptist. At some point, a portion of the documents were mounted. There does not appear to be a particular reason why some were mounted and some were not.
  - Accounting Notes, 1796-1825, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Hymns, Poetry, and Narratives, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Notes and Ephemera, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Mounted Official Materials and Notes, 1771-1776, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Mounted Notes and Ephemera, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)